Yousaf K H

DevOps Engineer



Resourceful DevOps Engineer with 4+ years of hands-on experience in Linux, AWS Operations, Deployments of Micro service applications and Developing CI/CD pipelines. Seeking a challenging position in an esteemed organization where my skills and knowledge can be improved and utilized effectively in order to contribute to the growth of the company.

Personal Info

Address

Thrissur, Kerala, India Pin: 679532

DOB

February 3rd, 1997

Phone

+917736720639

E-mail

yousaf.k.hamza@gmail.com

Skype

live:yousaf.k.hamza

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/yousafkhamza

GitHub

github.com/yousafkhamza

Website

https://yousafkhamza.online/

Achievements

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate (ID: HBBNPKGJM2141MGH)
- LFS169: Introduction to GitOps (ID: LF-jxy3zh8227)
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations Certified Associate (ID: 7935644OCIBF2021)

Skills

AWS:

ECS, Elastic Beanstalk, Kinesis, IAM, EC2, EBS, ELB, S3, EFS, VPC, RDS, Glue, Lambda Functions, Autoscaling, Route53

Work History

2021-08 -Present

DevOps Engineer - Qunatiphi, Trivandrum

- Designed and implemented web application updates and upgrades, monitoring performance to eliminate errors.
- Measured software performance using preagreed metrics.
- Wrote maintenance procedures for software to help users and administrators get the most from designs.
- Handled configuration management using bestsuited software tools, including Terraform, and CloudFormation.
- Maintained advanced security measures to protect user assets, safeguarding the integrity of confidential data.
- Build Elastic Beanstalk environments through CI/CD.
- Build Python based AWS Lambda Functions for automation.
- Managing AWS Billing and Cost explorer with best practices.

2020-06 -2021-08

System Engineer (Cloud) - Armia Systems, Kochi

- Implemented CI/CD for applications based on DevOps Best practices.
- Designed DevOps infrastructure from scratch for 3 product lines.
- Built CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins, AWS Codepipeline, Gitlab CI.
- Implemented Infrastructure As Code (IaC) using Terraform templates
- Eliminated extended downtime of the server network and processes by installing and configuring a Nagios server to monitor client servers.
- Fixed issues like spamming, Phishing Attempts, Network Security Attacks, Denial of Service, Botnet Attacks, etc, and provided server security.

Configuration Tools/IAC:

Ansible, Terraform, CloudFormation

Scripting:

Python(Intermediate), Bash,

Containerization:

Docker, K8s

CI/CD:

Jenkins, Codepipeline, GitHub Actions, Concourse CI

Monitoring tools:

Nagios, AWS Cloudwatch, Grafana, Prometheus

Web Servers:

Apache, Nginx

Firewalls:

CSF, IPTABLES, UFW, Windows Firewall

OS:

Linux, Ubuntu, Kali Linux, Windows

Other:

Atlassian Tools

2018-08 -2020-02

Systems Engineer – Activelobby IS, Kochi

- Managed AWS cloud Infrastructure.
- Automated tasks using Ansible
- Analysed client requirements and built cost effective, highly available and scalable server architecture in AWS Cloud.
- Created Lambda functions using Python and boto3 for managing AWS resources.
- Provided L2 support to multiple clients through various support Desks.
- Setup monitoring tools like Nagios and Amazon CloudWatch
- Optimizing and securing the production servers by using lptables, CSF, UFW and tweaking the kernel parameters.
- Managed VPS, Dedicated and shared servers
- Managed Internal Network, AD, Firewall etc Using FortiGate.

2018-06 -2018-08

Linux Administrator Intern - Clado Solutions, Kochi

- Installed OS(RHEL and Centos 6,7) on the servers and VM's, set up of working environment.
- Managed users and groups and assigning file access privileges, ACL, as per the requirement.
- Experience in Package management using RPM,YUM.
- Configured and managed Linux Virtual Machines.
- Setup LAMP servers in different flavours of Linux OS.

Education

2014-06 - 2018-06	Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science	
2010-00	North East Frontier Technical Universit	y CGPA: 6.93
2012-06 -	VHSE: Computer Science	
2014-06	GVHSS Desamangalam	Percentage: 67%
2011-03 -	SSLC	
2012-03	GVHSS Desamangalam	Percentage: 63%